Federico Joaquín Garcia

With 3 years of experience as a Software Developer, I have implemented new modules and functionalities for ERP software, improving administrative, sales, and management processes for multiple clients. I have also participated in government projects, playing key roles in development and decisions related to requirements engineering, design, infrastructure, and implementation of both custom-built applications and SaaS solutions.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Servicios & consultoría

Córdoba, Argentina

FullStack developer - Django/Next.js

July 2023 - Present

- Developed a complete API for a document digitization project for the municipality of Berazategui, using Django Rest Framework and Amazon Web Services (AWS) Textract OCR, reducing manual data entry by 80%.
- Designed a DER data schema, architecture diagram, and participated in decision-making for Project Sonia, which involves an LLM with user-customized context and domain, and a SaaS application with an interactive interface for viewing conversations and statistics.
- Configured and developed solutions using various AWS services, including Lambdas and Cognito middleware for managing user authorization and authentication.
- Set up WebSocket connections for both Django and Next.js, creating a Python consumer that listens to notifications from PostgreSQL and uses Redux on the client side to update the state of conversations in Sonia in real-time.

2GSOFT

Córdoba, Argentina

PL/SQL Developer - IT Support - DBA - ERP Software

October 2021 - July 2023

- Implemented custom client reports to optimize decision-making, using PL/SQL, Oracle Reports, and Oracle Apex, and developed complex queries.
- Modified functionalities and developed packages of functions, stored procedures, triggers, and materialized views according to each business's requirements. Additionally, developed new modules and views with Oracle Forms.
- Worked on database maintenance, ensuring data integrity, as well as installation and configuration of its infrastructure on Oracle Linux. Provided user support.

Freelance Developer

Córdoba, Argentina

FrontEnd Developer

January 2020 - Present

• Created custom static web pages for clients, using Next.js Framework and vanilla HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Improved SEO positioning and increased traffic by 40%.

EDUCATION

SIGLO XXI UNIVERSITY

Córdoba, Argentina

Software Engineering Student

Current

UNIVERSIDAD TECNOLÓGICA NACIONAL (UTN - NATIONAL TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY)

Córdoba, Argentina

Systems Engineering Student

2020 - 2023

COLEGIO DE LA INMACULADA

High School Diploma in Economics and Administration General average: 8 (eight) Córdoba, Argentina

2014-2019

LANGUAGES, SKILLS, AND AWARDS

- "Ishiki" Best social impact company in Latin America. Recognized by Delta Airlines COY 2019, Junior Achievement in Punta Cana.
- Native Spanish, English B2.